<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/introduction/</guid><description>To continue our growth, we need an eco-system which supports that. We are building that new eco-system and want you to be successful in it.
This site will tell you everything you need to know about our new architecture and the Architecture Principles which lie at its foundation.
When Degreed started, life was relatively simple. There weren&amp;rsquo;t a lot of features to maintain, clients to please or fellow developers to collaborate with.</description></item><item><title>Unbundling the Database</title><link>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/unbundling-the-database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 11:48:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/unbundling-the-database/</guid><description>Scalability We will continue to experience tremendous growth as a business and our data store needs to accommodate this. Growing your data store means that you are breaking it into smaller, horizontal pieces. Pieces which you are then able to grow vertically.
We have chosen to divide our data layer around the areas of our business. In Domain Driven Design it&amp;rsquo;s often referred to as a &amp;ldquo;Bounded Context&amp;rdquo;. This will not only give us more scaling options, but also enable us to optimize our data store, specific to the needs of that context.</description></item><item><title>Detangling the Monolith</title><link>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/detangling-the-monolith/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 11:50:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://degreed.github.io/architecture/docs/prologue/detangling-the-monolith/</guid><description>By implementing application services, we will reduce the cognitive load required to make changes. We also increase autonomy, the ability to aply the optimal solution to your problem, not being hindered by dependencies outside of your domain.
What do they contain? Application services are units of business logic which act on changes within the business. That&amp;rsquo;s all they contain, business logic. The application services sit on top of our Domain API&amp;rsquo;s and preferably have a one-to-one relation with them.</description></item></channel></rss>